<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0" xml:base="https://uisuite.net/">
  <channel>
    <title>UI Suite Initiative website - Design Systems with Drupal</title>
    <link>https://uisuite.net/</link>
    <description><![CDATA[Design Systems with Drupal]]></description>
    <language>en</language>
        <atom:link rel="self" href="https://uisuite.net/rss.xml"/>
<lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 23:14:17 +0200</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 25 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<item>
  <title>UI Suite Monthly #25 - Celebrating 5 Years with Major Releases and Growing Community</title>
  <link>https://uisuite.net/ui-suite-monthly-25-celebrating-5-years-anniversary</link>
  <description>&lt;p&gt;We marked a significant milestone in our &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_suite/issues/3503353"&gt;March 2025 monthly meeting&lt;/a&gt;, celebrating five years of organized development while announcing major releases and demonstrating growing community momentum. Our meeting showcased substantial progress across our ecosystem of design system modules for Drupal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Overall Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_suite/issues/3503353"&gt;25th monthly meeting&lt;/a&gt; highlighted our evolution from scattered tools to a cohesive design system implementation platform. We celebrated our 5th anniversary since going public, with two major module releases now integrated into Drupal core. Our meeting featured 14-15 participants discussing recent achievements, including &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns"&gt;UI Patterns 2.0&lt;/a&gt;'s successful release after 18 months of development, new icon API integration in Drupal core, and expanding adoption metrics showing 30 new installations weekly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have successfully positioned ourselves as a bridge technology while Drupal CMS explores Experience Builder, with &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns"&gt;UI Patterns 2&lt;/a&gt; teaching the community component-based development practices. Our meeting demonstrated increasing community engagement through Reddit posts, Slack activity, and growing statistics across all our projects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Key Topics Discussed&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI Patterns 2.0 Success and UI Patterns UI Demo -&lt;/strong&gt; Our flagship module completed its challenging 18-month development cycle with a 20-person team. Our release introduced UI Patterns UI, a new interface allowing content editors to configure components widgets without developer intervention. Christian demonstrated the field UI-like functionality, showing how different form modes can be created for varying contributor experiences, making our powerful but complex system more user-friendly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Icon API Integration Achievement -&lt;/strong&gt; We celebrated getting our Icon API directly into Drupal 11.1 core through the navigation module. This integration provides official icon pack usage and enables broader adoption across core modules, with plans for field integration and enhanced developer experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI Suite Bootstrap Theme Improvements -&lt;/strong&gt; Significant updates to our Bootstrap implementation included comprehensive component library enhancements using &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns"&gt;UI Patterns 2&lt;/a&gt; stories system. We addressed modal handling issues, CKEditor 5 integration problems, and expanded component demonstrations beyond official Bootstrap documentation to include edge cases and extreme usage scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design System Theme Updates -&lt;/strong&gt; Multiple theme implementations received updates: Daisy UI completed migration to version 5 in just two days, demonstrating the power of our UI framework; DSFR (French government design system) progressed toward 1.1.0 release candidate; and various ecosystem themes advanced &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns"&gt;UI Patterns 2&lt;/a&gt; compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community Growth and Adoption Metrics&lt;/strong&gt; Our community crossed 300 members and continues growing monthly. &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns"&gt;UI Patterns&lt;/a&gt; gained popularity ranking around 500th most popular Drupal module. We addressed composer namespace conflicts affecting field group integration and discussed case study development to showcase agency implementations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology Discussions&lt;/strong&gt; Our meeting included spirited debates about Tailwind CSS adoption, with team members expressing divided opinions on utility-first frameworks versus component-based approaches. We also discussed Adobe Spectrum integration possibilities and addressed questions about component filtering and organization.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Key Action Points&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Immediate Development Priorities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have prioritized finalizing UI Patterns UI for our spring 2.1 release targeted for the May-July timeframe, representing a major milestone in making our powerful but complex system more accessible to content editors. Our key immediate tasks include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Complete &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns"&gt;UI Patterns 2&lt;/a&gt; documentation updates for both users and developers&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Release UI Styles 2 and investigate Styles API integration into Drupal core&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Address composer namespace conflicts affecting field group and space modules&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Implement seasonal release schedule with spring (2.1) and summer (2.2) versions&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community and Documentation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our community engagement efforts focus on developing compelling case studies that showcase real agency projects using &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns"&gt;UI Patterns 2&lt;/a&gt;, providing concrete examples for potential adopters while promoting participating agencies. We recognize the urgent need to replace our current documentation strategy:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Update drupal.org documentation to replace outdated and confusing content&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Expand component library demonstrations with extreme use cases and edge scenarios&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Create presentation materials for upcoming conferences and local events&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Develop case studies showcasing agency implementations&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Roadmap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our technical roadmap emphasizes progressive migration of &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns"&gt;UI Patterns 2&lt;/a&gt; components into Drupal core, building on our success with Icon API integration in the navigation module. Our development priorities include advancing field support for UI Icons in core alongside existing navigation functionality, while exploring new opportunities:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Move &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns"&gt;UI Patterns 2&lt;/a&gt; components into Drupal core progressively&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Develop animation and transition features as the final major UI Suite artifact&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Explore Adobe Spectrum theme implementation opportunities&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Continue icon pack expansion with core modules and third-party systems&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conference and Outreach&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our conference participation centers around confirmed speaker participation at &lt;a href="https://events.drupal.org/atlanta2025"&gt;DrupalCon Atlanta&lt;/a&gt;, with strategic plans to maximize community exposure through multiple UI Suite-related proposals for &lt;a href="https://events.drupal.org/vienna2025"&gt;DrupalCon Vienna&lt;/a&gt;. We will leverage existing professional relationships to explore collaboration opportunities:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Organize contributor tables and networking opportunities at events&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Submit multiple UI Suite proposals for &lt;a href="https://events.drupal.org/vienna2025"&gt;DrupalCon Vienna&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Engage with Adobe Spectrum team members for potential collaboration&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Upcoming Deadlines / Releases&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table class="table"&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Release/Event&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Timeline&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Status&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;UI Patterns 2.1 (Spring Release)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;May - July 2025&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;In Development&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Includes UI Patterns UI feature&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;UI Patterns 2.2 (Summer Release)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;August - September 2025&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Planned&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Seasonal release schedule&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;DSFR 1.1.0 Release Candidate&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Next Month (April 2025)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Nearly Complete&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;French government design system&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;UI Styles 2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;June 2025&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Planned&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Second semester target&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Bootstrap 5.1 Release&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Immediately after meeting&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Ready&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Modal fixes and component improvements&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;DrupalCon Atlanta&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Next Week (March 2025)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Confirmed&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Design systems presentation&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;DrupalCon Belgium&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;April 11, 2025&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Scheduled&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;ATC presentation planned&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;DrupalCon Belgrade&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;June 2025&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Proposal Phase&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Multiple UI Suite presentations planned&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Case Studies Publication&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Next Month (April 2025)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;In Progress&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Agency project showcases&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Styles API Core Integration&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Second Semester 2025&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Research Phase&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Core contribution target&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our meeting concluded with our community reaching 300 members, demonstrating sustained growth and engagement. We expressed optimism, viewing our work as essential preparation for the Drupal community's component-based future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
  <comments>https://github.com/mika2na/mika2na.github.io/issues/4</comments>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">665b3157-69d8-4c28-9b4b-445fdf731e6b</guid>
          <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 25 18:00:00 +0100
</pubDate>
          <source url="https://uisuite.net/rss.xml">UI Suite Initiative website - Design Systems with Drupal</source>
          <dc:creator>G4MBINI</dc:creator>
          <dc:subject>Monthly meeting, drupal-planet</dc:subject>
          </item>
<item>
  <title>UI Suite Monthly #04 - Bridging Core Integration and Drupal 10 Compatibility</title>
  <link>https://uisuite.net/ui-suite-monthly-04-bridging-core-integration-and-drupal-10-compatibility</link>
  <description>&lt;h2&gt;Overall Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We held our fourth monthly meeting to discuss progress on our ecosystem of Drupal UI modules, including &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns"&gt;UI Patterns&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_styles"&gt;UI Styles&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_skins"&gt;UI Skins&lt;/a&gt;, and related components. Our meeting covered significant developments in Drupal 10 compatibility, major architectural discussions with Drupal core maintainers, and our community coordination efforts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Key highlights include our productive meeting with core maintainers about the Single Directory Component (SDC) project and UI component initiatives, our successful releases achieving Drupal 10 compatibility across the ecosystem, and ongoing discussions about our module consolidation and community governance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Key Topics Discussed&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Core Integration Discussions&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We had a significant meeting with core maintainers on December 23rd about the SDC (Single Directory Component) project and UI component in core initiative. Core maintainers proposed that our &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns"&gt;UI Patterns&lt;/a&gt; could become a wrapper around SDC, with &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns"&gt;UI Patterns&lt;/a&gt; serving as a model to expose the component API. This would require substantial architectural changes and potentially breaking changes for our &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns"&gt;UI Patterns module&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Drupal 10 Compatibility Progress&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our ecosystem has made substantial progress on Drupal 10 compatibility. Most of our important modules are now compatible, with approximately half of our &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns/ecosystem"&gt;UI Patterns ecosystem&lt;/a&gt; successfully converted. Some modules still require our attention, including components maintained by Alex and Christian that need our community outreach.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Module Ecosystem Management&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We discussed the management of related modules like Display Suite and &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns_ds"&gt;UI Patterns Display Suite&lt;/a&gt;. Our team debated whether to maintain separate modules or consolidate functionality directly into our &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns"&gt;UI Patterns&lt;/a&gt; core, considering both maintenance burden and community needs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;UI Styles and UI Skins Consistency&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We had major discussions focused on achieving consistency across our UI ecosystem, particularly regarding:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Grouping and sorting mechanisms for our styles and patterns&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Form configuration consistency between our &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_styles"&gt;UI Styles&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_skins"&gt;UI Skins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Implementation of alphabetical sorting with optional weighting systems&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Plugin definition class improvements and breaking changes&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;CKEditor 5 Integration&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We reported progress on CKEditor 5 integration for our &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_styles"&gt;UI Styles&lt;/a&gt;, with PHP implementation completed and JavaScript development planned as our next phase.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Community Initiative Status&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We discussed promoting our &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_suite"&gt;UI Suite&lt;/a&gt; as an official Drupal community initiative, recognizing our need for better organization and formal recognition within the broader Drupal community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Key Action Points&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Immediate Actions&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact Antonio and maintainers&lt;/strong&gt;: We need to reach out to module maintainers for Drupal 10 compatibility assistance&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open GitHub issues&lt;/strong&gt;: We must create issues for patent consolidation discussions&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Display Suite evaluation&lt;/strong&gt;: We need to assess whether our Display Suite modules should be integrated into UI Patterns or maintained separately&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Module maintainer outreach&lt;/strong&gt;: We must contact Christian and Alex regarding module maintenance and compatibility&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Development Tasks&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI Styles 1.4 release&lt;/strong&gt;: We need to complete views integration and CKEditor 5 compatibility&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grouping implementation&lt;/strong&gt;: We must add consistent grouping and sorting mechanisms across our &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_styles"&gt;UI Styles&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_skins"&gt;UI Skins&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns"&gt;UI Patterns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plugin definition updates&lt;/strong&gt;: We need to implement breaking changes for improved API consistency&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layout Builder regression&lt;/strong&gt;: We must address ongoing issues with our Layout Builder compatibility&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Documentation and Community&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Change records&lt;/strong&gt;: We need to create documentation for breaking changes in our plugin definitions&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue queue management&lt;/strong&gt;: We must ensure our issues don't stagnate and maintain active development momentum&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community initiative application&lt;/strong&gt;: We should explore registering our &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_suite"&gt;UI Suite&lt;/a&gt; as an official Drupal community initiative&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Upcoming Deadlines / Releases&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table class="table"&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Module/Component&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Version&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Target Release&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Key Features&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Status&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;UI Styles&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Q1 2023&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Views integration, CKEditor 5 compatibility&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;In Development&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;UI Patterns&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;TBD&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Before Drupal 10.1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;SDC wrapper integration, plugin discovery updates&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Planning Phase&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;UI Skins&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;TBD&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Q1 2023&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Consistency improvements, grouping features&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;In Development&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Layout Options&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.1+&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Ongoing&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Bug fixes, Drupal 10 compatibility&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Maintenance&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;UI Patterns Extended&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Beta 3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;TBD&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Christian's updates (details pending)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Pending Update&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Critical Dependencies&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drupal 10.1 release&lt;/strong&gt;: Our UI component integration timeline depends on core release schedule&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SDC project timeline&lt;/strong&gt;: Our &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns"&gt;UI Patterns&lt;/a&gt; architectural changes tied to Single Directory Component availability&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community maintainer availability&lt;/strong&gt;: Several of our updates dependent on volunteer maintainer capacity&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Next Meeting&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;: February 14, 2023 (rescheduled from February 7th) &lt;strong&gt;Focus&lt;/strong&gt;: Follow-up on our SDC discussions, development progress review, and our community initiative planning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our UI Suite Initiative continues to be a vital community-driven effort to improve Drupal's component ecosystem. Community members interested in contributing can join our dedicated Slack channel and participate in our monthly meetings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
  <comments>https://github.com/mika2na/mika2na.github.io/issues/31</comments>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">88364d83-5549-4b15-8adf-357922cb47ed</guid>
          <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 23 14:00:00 +0100
</pubDate>
          <source url="https://uisuite.net/rss.xml">UI Suite Initiative website - Design Systems with Drupal</source>
          <dc:creator>G4MBINI</dc:creator>
          <dc:subject>drupal-planet</dc:subject>
          </item>
<item>
  <title>UI Suite Monthly #03 - December 2022 Progress Update</title>
  <link>https://uisuite.net/ui-suite-monthly-03-december-2022-progress-update</link>
  <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_suite"&gt;UI Suite Initiative&lt;/a&gt; represents our ambitious effort to bring comprehensive design system capabilities to Drupal through a collection of interconnected modules. As organizations increasingly adopt design systems to maintain consistency across digital properties, we recognize the critical need for robust tooling within content management systems. Our December 2022 meeting captured a pivotal moment for our project, occurring just as Drupal 10 was launching and as we introduced innovative features like dynamic CSS variable management.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Overall Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We held our &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_suite/issues/3319719"&gt;third monthly meeting on December 13, 2022&lt;/a&gt;, discussing progress on our comprehensive set of Drupal modules designed to implement Design Systems. Our &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_suite"&gt;UI Suite&lt;/a&gt; consists of independent but interconnected modules that provide a unified experience for building design system components in Drupal. The meeting covered our upcoming Drupal 10 compatibility, module releases, new features like our &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_skins"&gt;UI Skins module for CSS variable management&lt;/a&gt;, and ongoing discussions about module organization and security coverage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Key Topics Discussed&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drupal 10 Compatibility&lt;/strong&gt; We announced that Drupal 10 would be released the following day (December 14, 2022), with the 9-to-10 upgrade being easier than the previous 8-to-9 transition. Several of our UI Suite modules are already prepared for compatibility, including some that our team members can update independently (FIFA, matter flag, settings decoupled) and others requiring coordination with external maintainers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Module Releases and Updates&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;We released UI Patterns beta 2 in early November with prefixes and history improvements&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Page Designer version 1.2 was released the previous week&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;We have plans for &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_styles/releases/8.x-1.3"&gt;UI Styles 1.3 release&lt;/a&gt; with Views integration and minor compatibility breaks in library Twig files&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;We discussed moving to more frequent releases with fewer features rather than waiting for comprehensive updates&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security Coverage Initiative&lt;/strong&gt; We discussed applying for security coverage for our modules as they mature and gain stable releases. This involves specific processes on drupal.org that require particular permissions and roles, with some complexity around maintainer access rights.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Module: UI Skins&lt;/strong&gt; A significant portion of our meeting focused on demonstrating &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_skins"&gt;UI Skins&lt;/a&gt;, our new module that integrates CSS variables (custom properties) with theme management. Our module allows dynamic color and styling changes through a configuration interface, demonstrated with Material Design integration. Our system maintains semantic color meanings while allowing visual customization.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pattern Sorting Enhancement&lt;/strong&gt; We reviewed a merge request for sorting our &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns"&gt;UI Patterns&lt;/a&gt; definitions alphabetically by label rather than machine name, improving user experience in pattern selection interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layout Builder Integration&lt;/strong&gt; We discussed ongoing issues with Layout Builder integration, noting that only a minority of our team members actively use Layout Builder, which sometimes delays bug discovery. We mentioned a bug fix for &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_styles"&gt;UI Styles&lt;/a&gt; in Layout Builder contexts as upcoming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Key Action Points&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release Management&lt;/strong&gt;: We will proceed with more frequent, incremental releases rather than waiting for complete feature sets&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security Coverage&lt;/strong&gt;: We will apply for security coverage for our mature modules after Drupal 10 release&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI Skins Development&lt;/strong&gt;: We will continue development of our CSS variables integration module with focus on Material Design and Bootstrap compatibility&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pattern Sorting&lt;/strong&gt;: We will merge our alphabetical sorting improvement for pattern definitions&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Layout Builder Support&lt;/strong&gt;: We will address remaining Layout Builder integration issues and consider broader adoption patterns&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community Engagement&lt;/strong&gt;: We will respond to inquiries about Single Directory Components and schedule follow-up meetings&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Upcoming Deadlines / Releases&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table class="table"&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Module/Item&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Target Release&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Status&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Drupal 10&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;December 14, 2022&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Imminent&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Day after our meeting&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;UI Patterns&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Same day as meeting&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;In Progress&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Our democratic decision to release with available features&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;UI Styles 1.3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Short term&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Planned&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Views integration, minor breaking changes&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;UI Skins Alpha&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Soon&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;In Development&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;CSS variables integration, Material Design tested&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Pattern Sorting Fix&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Same day as meeting&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Ready for merge&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Awaiting our final review&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Layout Builder Bug Fix&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;"For Christmas"&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Planned&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;UI Styles Layout Builder integration fix&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Security Coverage Applications&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;After Drupal 10 release&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Planned&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;For all our mature modules&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Our Next Team Meeting&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;January 10, 2023, 11 AM&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Scheduled&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Maintaining our monthly cadence&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our meeting demonstrated our project's momentum toward Drupal 10 compatibility while introducing innovative features like dynamic theming through CSS variables, positioning our &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_suite"&gt;UI Suite&lt;/a&gt; as a comprehensive solution for design system implementation in Drupal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
  <comments>https://github.com/mika2na/mika2na.github.io/issues/6</comments>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">b14890ab-5138-41f4-a5ea-292f1cfb43f4</guid>
          <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 22 14:00:00 +0100
</pubDate>
          <source url="https://uisuite.net/rss.xml">UI Suite Initiative website - Design Systems with Drupal</source>
          <dc:creator>G4MBINI</dc:creator>
          <dc:subject>drupal-planet</dc:subject>
          </item>
<item>
  <title>UI Suite Monthly #02 - Progress Updates and New Module Introduction</title>
  <link>https://uisuite.net/ui-suite-monthly-02-progress-updates-and-new-module-introduction</link>
  <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_suite"&gt;UI Suite Initiative&lt;/a&gt; held its &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_suite/issues/3317006"&gt;second monthly meeting on November 8, 2022&lt;/a&gt;, bringing together contributors to discuss ongoing developments, introduce new modules, and address key technical challenges facing the Drupal component ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Overall Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This meeting served as a comprehensive update on the &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_suite"&gt;UI Suite ecosystem&lt;/a&gt;'s evolution, covering everything from administrative changes to new module introductions. The team addressed the migration from GitHub to Drupal.org's issue queue, discussed code consolidation strategies, and introduced important terminology clarifications around "slots" and "props" borrowed from Vue.js concepts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A significant portion of the meeting focused on introducing &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_skins"&gt;UI Skins&lt;/a&gt;, the fifth module in the &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_suite"&gt;UI Suite family&lt;/a&gt;, designed to handle global CSS variables and theme settings. The session concluded with a practical demonstration of the Material Design implementation using the new UI Skins module, showcasing real-time color and layout adjustments through a configuration interface.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Key Topics Discussed&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Issue Queue Migration and GitHub Status&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The team confirmed the successful migration to Drupal.org's issue queue while noting that GitHub issue creation remains technically possible. The last GitHub issue was created on September 15, before the &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns/releases/8.x-1.3"&gt;UI Patterns 1.3 release&lt;/a&gt;. Contributors are working to find ways to disable GitHub issue creation without deleting existing issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Code Consolidation Strategy&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ongoing discussion about consolidating the five UI Pattern modules continues. Current modules include the core library plus two modules related to Core API and two for contributed APIs. The team is considering whether to move contributed modules out of UI Patterns or bring certain contributed modules into the main project, with input needed from Antonio and Fabian.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Slots vs Props Terminology&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The team formalized vocabulary borrowed from Vue.js to distinguish between two types of component data:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slots&lt;/strong&gt;: Free renderable content (strings, elements, or renderable objects) that can be thrown into templates&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Props&lt;/strong&gt;: Rigid types with specific value requirements (booleans, URLs, specific values)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This distinction helps clarify component architecture and data constraints, with the proposal to use "fields" for slots and "settings" for props in &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns"&gt;UI Patterns&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;UI Styles Type Options Module Discovery&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The team discovered a competing module called "Type Options" that shares similarities with &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_styles"&gt;UI Styles&lt;/a&gt;. Created around the same time, it follows &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_styles"&gt;UI Styles&lt;/a&gt; philosophy by declaring everything in YAML files and generating plugins. The module offers two integrations: one with Layered Plugin and another with Paragraph types. The team plans to contact the maintainers to explore potential collaboration or merging.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Introduction of UI Skins Module&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The meeting's major announcement was &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_skins"&gt;UI Skins&lt;/a&gt;, the fifth module in the UI Suite ecosystem. This module implements three key features:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global CSS Variables&lt;/strong&gt;: CSS properties that enable theme-wide customization&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theme Settings Integration&lt;/strong&gt;: Allows front-end developers to edit YAML files instead of custom PHP code&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design System Support&lt;/strong&gt;: Enables features like dark mode, light mode, and other theme variations&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Documentation Migration Discussion&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The team debated moving documentation from GitHub Pages to Drupal.org's documentation system. This would allow broader community participation in documentation maintenance and ensure consistency across the ecosystem. The current documentation consists of approximately eight pages that would need to be converted from RST format.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Library Sorting Standards&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A discussion arose about standardizing how patterns and styles are sorted in libraries. The team decided to sort by labels (visible to users) rather than machine names, making the interface more user-friendly for site builders and clients who interact with the pattern libraries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Key Action Points&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scope Lock for UI Patterns 1.4&lt;/strong&gt;: Finalize the scope and stop adding new features to ensure release progression&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GitHub Issue Migration&lt;/strong&gt;: Contributors wanting specific GitHub issues addressed must create corresponding Drupal.org issues and migrate their merge requests&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI Skins Testing&lt;/strong&gt;: Expand testing beyond Material Design to include additional themes, with Bootstrap 5 presenting particular challenges due to CSS variable complexity&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Documentation Migration&lt;/strong&gt;: Convert eight pages of documentation from GitHub to Drupal.org format&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Type Options Module Outreach&lt;/strong&gt;: Contact the Type Options module maintainers to explore collaboration opportunities&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monthly Meeting Structure&lt;/strong&gt;: Implement a formal issue queue for meeting preparation and reporting&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Terminology Standardization&lt;/strong&gt;: Begin implementing the slots/props (fields/settings) terminology across UI Bootstrap and other implementations&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Upcoming Deadlines / Releases&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table class="table"&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Module/Project&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Target Release&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Scope Status&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Key Features&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;UI Patterns 1.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Before next meeting&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Scope locked - 12-13 issues&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Wishlist-based improvements, GitHub issue migration&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;UI Styles&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;New release planned&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;API improvements in progress&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Views integration, testing requirements&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;UI Skins&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Alpha/Internal release&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Material Design working&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Global CSS variables, theme settings&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;CKEditor 5 Migration&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;December 2022 (tentative)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Dependent on project needs&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;After UI Skins and UI Styles stabilization&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Next Monthly Meeting&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;December 13, 2022&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Meeting preparation&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Avoiding holiday conflicts&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Bootstrap 5 Implementation&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;TBD&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Challenges with CSS variables&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Complex variable exposure issues&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;The meeting demonstrated the &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_suite"&gt;UI Suite Initiative&lt;/a&gt;'s continued momentum, with active development across multiple modules and a clear roadmap for upcoming releases. The introduction of UI Skins represents a significant step forward in providing comprehensive theming capabilities for Drupal component-based architectures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
  <comments>https://github.com/mika2na/mika2na.github.io/issues/5</comments>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">1ce9e6a6-73ab-4a94-bc72-ce236c397452</guid>
          <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 22 14:00:00 +0100
</pubDate>
          <source url="https://uisuite.net/rss.xml">UI Suite Initiative website - Design Systems with Drupal</source>
          <dc:creator>G4MBINI</dc:creator>
          <dc:subject>drupal-planet</dc:subject>
          </item>
<item>
  <title>UI Suite Monthly #01 - Progress Update and Future Roadmap</title>
  <link>https://uisuite.net/ui-suite-monthly-01-progress-update-future-roadmap</link>
  <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_suite"&gt;UI Suite Initiative&lt;/a&gt; held its &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_suite/issues/3314689"&gt;first monthly meeting on October 11, 2022&lt;/a&gt;, bringing together developers and contributors to discuss the current state of the project and plan for future developments. This comprehensive session covered recent achievements, upcoming releases, and important architectural decisions that will shape the future of UI component development in Drupal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Overall Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_suite"&gt;UI Suite Initiative&lt;/a&gt; aims to implement full Design Systems in Drupal, expanding beyond the current offerings of components, solutions, layouts, and examples. The project's dual mission focuses on preserving and improving the developer building experience while creating implementation value without requiring PHP expertise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The meeting highlighted significant progress made in September, including the anticipated &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns"&gt;UI Patterns&lt;/a&gt; release and improved compatibility with PHP 8.1 and Drupal 10. A major milestone was the development move to drupal.org, centralizing repository management, CI processes, and issue tracking. The team also discussed two complex technical subjects: the proposed UI Theme module for CSS variable management and the ongoing debate around type validation and field filtering in &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns"&gt;UI Patterns&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Key Topics Discussed&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Recent Achievements and Releases&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI Patterns Updates&lt;/strong&gt;: The team delivered the expected &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns"&gt;UI Patterns&lt;/a&gt; release in late September, featuring enhanced PHP 8.1 and Drupal 10 compatibility. Development has officially moved to drupal.org, streamlining the contribution process and issue management.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI Patterns Settings Evolution&lt;/strong&gt;: Version 2.0 beta was released with substantial new features, creating a significant gap between branch 1.x and 2.x. The module has become particularly valuable for Layout Builder configurations, offering numerous widgets for sidebar customization.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design System Implementation&lt;/strong&gt;: Two new themes were released in alpha - Protocol and Material - serving as crucial testing grounds for UI Suite modules. These implementations help validate use cases when working with existing design systems rather than custom client projects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Proposed UI Theme Module&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The team discussed creating a new module (tentatively called "UI Theme") to handle CSS variable management and theming capabilities. This module would address the need for runtime-changeable design tokens, similar to how Bootstrap allows primary color customization or Material Design supports theme variations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Key features would include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;YAML-based configuration for design tokens&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Runtime CSS variable modification&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Integration with existing design systems&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Support for accessibility themes (light/dark modes)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;UI for site builders to define theme settings&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Type Validation and Field Architecture&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A significant portion of the meeting focused on improving &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns"&gt;UI Patterns&lt;/a&gt;' data handling and validation. The team identified four distinct use cases:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open Content Fields&lt;/strong&gt;: Where any data type can be injected (markup, strings, integers, arrays)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sequence/List Fields&lt;/strong&gt;: For looping operations requiring array structures&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Non-Markup Values&lt;/strong&gt;: Strictly typed fields for attributes that cannot contain markup&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Structured Data&lt;/strong&gt;: Specific data structures like Drupal menu items&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The discussion explored adopting React-like concepts of "props" and "slots" to better organize component data:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slots&lt;/strong&gt;: Content areas that can accept various data types (equivalent to current fields)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Props&lt;/strong&gt;: Typed properties for configuration and structured data (similar to &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns_settings"&gt;UI Patterns Settings&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Key Action Points&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Immediate Tasks&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Repository Management&lt;/strong&gt;: Contact Antonio regarding GitHub repository access to implement read-only status and redirect users to drupal.org&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue Migration&lt;/strong&gt;: Move remaining GitHub issues to Drupal's issue queue for centralized tracking&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Release Planning&lt;/strong&gt;: Finalize &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_patterns/releases/8.x-1.4"&gt;UI Patterns 1.4&lt;/a&gt; scope using the issue created by Michael that combines community wish lists&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Documentation&lt;/strong&gt;: Share presentation slides and video recording publicly&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Development Priorities&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI Styles Integration&lt;/strong&gt;: Expand compatibility beyond Layout Builder to include:&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;CKEditor 5 integration&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Views integration (currently in testing)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;General form integration for broader applicability&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UI Theme Module Development&lt;/strong&gt;: Begin specification and development of the CSS variable management system with YAML configuration support&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Architecture Review&lt;/strong&gt;: Consider props/slots implementation for better type safety and developer experience&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Community Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LinkedIn Group&lt;/strong&gt;: Continue building the 55-member community for sharing updates and discussions&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DrupalCon Planning&lt;/strong&gt;: Prepare for the next summer event in France (first French DrupalCon since 2009)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;: Engage with community feedback on component definition formats and typing requirements&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Upcoming Deadlines / Releases&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table class="table"&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Module/Component&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Version&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Status&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Expected Timeline&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Key Features&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;UI Patterns&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Planning&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Q4 2022&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Community-requested features, improved PHP 8.1/Drupal 10 support&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;UI Patterns Settings&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;2.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Beta&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Current&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Major feature expansion, Layout Builder enhancements&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;UI Styles&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Next Release&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Development&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Q1 2023&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;CKEditor 5 integration, Views support&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;UI Theme&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1.0&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Concept&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;TBD&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;CSS variable management, YAML configuration&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Protocol Theme&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Alpha&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Released&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Design system testing and validation&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Material Theme&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Alpha&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Released&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Design system testing and validation&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.drupal.org/project/ui_suite"&gt;UI Suite Initiative&lt;/a&gt; continues to evolve as a comprehensive solution for design system implementation in Drupal. The team's focus on developer experience, community feedback, and architectural improvements positions the project well for broader adoption and continued innovation in the Drupal ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
  <comments>https://github.com/mika2na/mika2na.github.io/issues/3</comments>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">92aa1f0d-4d8d-438a-9f4d-85e88f9f4790</guid>
          <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 22 14:00:00 +0200
</pubDate>
          <source url="https://uisuite.net/rss.xml">UI Suite Initiative website - Design Systems with Drupal</source>
          <dc:creator>G4MBINI</dc:creator>
          <dc:subject>drupal-planet</dc:subject>
          </item>
</channel>
</rss>
